Now that we have a database, we can take
advantage of an Android pattern to bind our view to
our data model known as a content provider. A content
provider allows us to think of our view data in
terms of URIs which is a convenient structure for
our applications. We can have views display different data based
upon which URI is currently active. As it turns out,
a URI is the primary data member for those Intents,
that Rato so gloriously described. With a combination
of content providers and intents, one can nicely
decouple the data being displayed from the view.
And there's one other great thing we get from
using URI with a data location. It's easy
to have our database notify components that are registered
to observe that location which causes our cursor
to update our list and show the latest data.
Content providers can return all sorts of data but typically, they return either
a list of items, or a single item. Here's how one might modify our
query to select the data for a specific date, rather than a range of
days which in this case also contains more information for the viewer to see.